Finding Aid for Arthur H. Vandenberg Papers, 1884-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Speeches
  - 1934
    - 1934 Final 1934 Campaign Speech. (Reel 6)
  - 1935
    - January 18, 1935 "The World Court (Reel 6)
    - February 15, 1935 "The 4, 880,000, 000 Appropriation Bill" (Reel 6)
    - May 8, 1935 "International Trade Relations of the United, States" (Reel 6)
    - June 20, 1935 "The Latest Constitutional Challenge" N.B.C. Radio, Washington (Reel 6)
    - July 7, 1935 "Federal Taxes-There is no Santa Claus" (Reel 6)
    - August 14, 1935 "The Tax Bill is Midsummer Madness" (Reel 6)
    - November 14, 1935 "Can America Stay out of the Next War?" Michigan Press Club, Ann Arbor (Reel 6)
    - December 6, 1935 "Com. Address for 18th Anniversary of Finnish Independence" Detroit. (Reel 6)
  - January-July 1936
    - February 12, 1936 "We Are at Crisis" Lincoln Day Address. New York. (Reel 6)
    - February 21, 1936 Radio Address on Supreme Court. Washington, D.C. (Reel 6)
    - March 2, 1936 "Layman's View of the Supreme Court" N.B.C. Radio. Washington, D.C. (Reel 6)
    - June 19, 1936 "Vampires on the Blood Stream of the Public Credit" (Reel 6)
    - July 4, 1936 Grand Rapids Campaign Speech. (Reel 6)
  - August-December 1936
    - August 6, 1936 Address to Union League Club. Chicago. (Reel 6)
    - September 17, 1936. Constitution Day Address. Chicago (Reel 6)
    - September 28, 1936 Grand Rapids Campaign Speech (Reel 6)
    - October 1, 1936 Philadelphia Campaign Speech (Reel 6)
  - Undated 1936
    - 1936 Wilmington, Delaware (Reel 6)
    - 1936 Scotts Bluff, Nebraska (Reel 6)
    - 1936 Omaha, Nebraska (Reel 6)
    - 1936 Ohio Radio Speech (Reel 6)
    - 1936 Connecticut (Reel 6)
    - 1936 Final Campaign Speech. Michigan. Radio. (Reel 6)
  - 1937
    - March 2, 1937, "Reorganization of the Federal Judiciary" (Reel 6)
    - June 22, 1937 "More Relief for Less Money" (Reel 6)
    - September 17, 1937 "150th Anniversary of the Adoption of the Constitution of the United States" Detroit. (Reel 6)
    - October 28, 1937 Speech to Joint meeting of Luncheon and Community Clubs. Grand Rapids. (Reel 6)
    - November 22, 1937 "Where do we go from Here?" Radio. (Reel 6)
    - December 2, 1937 "Federal-Aid Highway Appropriations" (Reel 6)
    - December 20, 1937 "Child Labor-Proposed Constitutional Amendment" (Reel 6)
    - September 1937 Veterans of Foreign Wars. Buffalo. (Reel 6)
  - January-June 1938
    - February 12, 1938 Lincoln Day Speech to Middlesex Club. Boston, Massachusetts (Reel 6)
    - May 30, 1938 Gettysburg Memorial Address. Gettysburg, PA (Reel 6)
    - June 16, 1938 "Monetary Problems" (Reel 6)
    - June 24, 1938 Address to Annual Banquet, Michigan State Bankers Association. Grand Rapids. (Reel 6)
    - June, 1938 Address to Graduates of Union College, Schenectady, NY (Reel 6)
  - July-August 1938
    - July 13, 1938 "Cherry Festival Address"' Traverse City, Michigan. (Reel 6)
    - September 1, 1938 Address to Western Michigan Conference of Rotary Clubs, Grand Rapids. (Reel 6)
    - August 14, 1938 Address to National Fraternal Congress. Detroit. (Reel 6)
    - August 28, 1938 Address to the Michigan Conference of Seventh-Day Adventists dedicating new auditorium. Grand Ledge, Michigan. (Reel 6)
  - September 1938
    - September 14, 1938 Address at Ninth Annual Northern Dinner of Miami's Committee of One Hundred. White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia (Reel 6)
    - September 17, 1938 Constitution Day Address. Chicago. (Reel 6)
    - September 28, 1938 Address to Michigan League of Women Voters. Saginaw, Michigan (Reel 6)
  - October 1938
    - October 3, 1938 Address to Michigan Republican State Convention. Grand Rapids, Michigan (Reel 6)
    - October 10, 1938 Address at rally of Lincoln Republican Club at Wichita, Kansas. (Reel 6)
    - October 11, 1938 Address in Sioux Falls, South Dakota (Reel 6)
    - October 29, 1938 Republican Rally at Columbus, Ohio and CBS Radio (Reel 6)
  - November-December 1938 1938 undated
    - November 4, 1938 WJR Radio. Detroit. (Reel 6)
    - December 2, 1938 Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. Symposium on Law in Modern Society. (Reel 6)
    - 1938 Memorial Address for Senator Royal S. Copeland. Dexter, Michigan (Reel 6)
    - 1938 Profit Sharing Investigation and Plans (Reel 6)
  - January-June 1939
    - February 21, 1939 "Put on the Brakes" (Reel 6)
    - February 27, 1939 "Peace or War for America" (Reel 6)
    - May 6, 1939 "The State of the Union" Annual Convention Banquet, Manufacturers Association of New Jersey." (Reel 6)
    - May 29, 1939 Remarks of Carl E. Mapes on AHV (Reel 6)
    - June 5, 1939 Syracuse Commencement Address (Reel 6)
  - July-December 1939
    - September 6, 1939 "Homecoming Day" Detroit at Michigan State Fair (2 speeches) (Reel 6)
    - September 18, 1939 Address to Republican Rally at Bay City, Michigan (Reel 6)
    - October 4, 1939 "Peace and Honor for America" (Reel 6)
    - November 3, 1939 Vandenberg's Statement on Trade Treaties (Reel 6)
    - December 5, 1939 Vandenberg's Statement on Breaking Relations with Russia (Reel 6)
  - January-March 1940
    - January 20, 1940 Memorial Address on William Borah (Reel 6)
    - February 10, 1940 "America at the Crossroads" St. Paul, Minnesota (Reel 6)
    - March 25, 1940 "Looking Ahead to Next November " (Reel 6)
    - March 27, 1940 "Reciprocal Trade Treaties" (Reel 6)
  - April-June 1940
    - April 13, 1940 Gridiron Club Address (Reel 6)
    - April 22, 1940 "Senator Vandenberg Supports Far-Reaching Investigation of Old-Age Problem with Particular Reference to the Social Security Act and the Townsend Plan" (Reel 6)
    - May 16, 1940 Address to Republican State Convention "On to Philadelphia" (Reel 6)
  - July-August 1940
    - August 12, 1940 "Volunteers Versus Conscripts" (Reel 6)
    - August 14, 1940 Address to Michigan Republican Service Men's League. (Reel 6)
  - September 1940
    - September 5, 1940 Speech at Battle Creek, Michigan (Reel 6)
    - September 13, 1940 "Our Worst Tax Law" (Reel 6)
    - September 16, 1940 Address to Kent County Republican Rally (Reel 6)
    - September 26, 1940 Address to Banquet preceding the Michigan, Republican State Convention (Reel 6)
  - October-December 1940 1940 undated
    - October 21, 1940 Address at Logansport, Indiana (Reel 6)
    - October 22, 1940 Detroit Safety Council (Reel 6)
    - October 23, 1940 State-Wide Radio Address. Detroit. (Reel 6)
    - October 26, 1940 National Radio Broadcast. Cleveland, Ohio (Reel 6)
    - October 29, 1940 "Labor Address." Flint, Michigan. (Reel 6)
    - December 2, 1940 Economic Defense Board" (Reel 6)
    - 1940 Statement (Speech) of Senator Vandenberg at Mt. Clemens. (Reel 6)
    - 1940 Public Statement on the "Stop Dewey" movement (Reel 6)
  - 1941
    - February 18, 1941 "Speech in opposition to Lend Lease" (Reel 7)
    - June 9, 1941 "Albion Commencement Address" Albion, Michigan (Reel 7)
    - August 5, 1941 "Extension of Selective Service" (Reel 7)
    - October 27, 1941 "The Case Against Repealing the Neutrality Act" (Reel 7)
    - 1941 "Churchill was here once before!" (Reel 7)
    - 1941 Address concerning America's national defense (Reel 7)
  - 1942
    - March 17, 1942 Speech on Senate Finance Committee work (Reel 7)
    - September 7, 1942 "The Truth About Taxes and Inflation" (Reel 7)
    - September 17, 1942 "Freezing Social-Security Taxes" (Reel 7)
    - October 29, 1942 Radio Campaign Speech. WJR. Detroit. (Reel 7)
    - November, 1942 "Republican Politics and War" (Reel 7)
    - November 1942, 1942 Campaign Speech (Reel 7)
  - January-May 1943
    - January 4, 1943 Vandenberg statement on Tugvell in Puerto Rico (Reel 7)
    - March 6, 1943 Statement of AHV on Florida Canal (Reel 7)
    - March 7, 1943 Radio Speech for Red Cross (Reel 7)
    - March 25, 1943 "Farm Prices" (Reel 7)
    - May 20, 1943 Trade Act (Reel 7)
    - May 24, 1943 Extending the Trade Agreement Act (Reel 7)
  - June-December 1943
    - June 2, 1943 Letter to President recommending Tax Bill (Reel 7)
    - June 26, 1943 "Connally-Smith Bill" (Reel 7)
    - July 1, 1943 "The Food Crisis" (Reel 7)
    - July 15, 1943 Statement on UNRRA Sub-Committee (Reel 7)
    - September 14, 1943 Letter to President Roosevelt re: Social Security Rates (Reel 7)
    - September 17, 1943 "Baruch Report on West Coast Man Power Problem" (Reel 7)
    - September 17, 1943 Statement relative to Baruch Report (Reel 7)
    - September 22, 1943 "The Mackinac Charter" (Reel 7)
    - October 25, 1943 "Senate Peace Resolution" (Reel 7)
    - November 19, 1943 Statement on Social Security Rates (Reel 7)
  - January-September 1944
    - January 11, 1944 "Social Security Freeze" (Reel 7)
    - February 11, 1944 "Subsidies and Inflation" (Reel 7)
    - February 16, 1944 UNRRA (Reel 7)
    - March 1691944 Statement at death of Charles L. McNary (Reel 7)
    - March 20, 1944 "Social Security" (Reel 7)
    - April 2, 1944 Polish Dinner. Detroit. (Reel 7)
    - April 12, 1944 "Poland's Post-War Status" (Reel 7)
    - April 28, 1944 Statement of Vandenberg for London Daily Mirror (Reel 7)
    - May 29, 1944 "Petrillo" (Reel 7)
    - August 9, 1944 "Post-War Jobs" (Reel 7)
    - August 22, 1944 "International Peace Machinery--the Dumbarton Oaks Conference" (Reel 7)
  - October-December 1944 1944 undated
    - October 4, 1944 Statement on Social Security Tax (Reel 7)
    - October 7, 1944 Michigan Presidential Campaign Speech (Reel 7)
    - October 1944 Michigan Campaign Speech (Reel 7)
    - October 1944 Final Michigan Campaign Speech for 1944 (Reel 7)
    - November 14, 1944 Social Security Freeze Statement (Reel 7)
    - November 22, 1944 "Saving Michigan 3250 000, 000 Taxes" (Reel 7)
    - December 6, 1944 Pearl Harbor Memorial Radio Address. Plea to Buy Bonds (Reel 7)
    - 1944 Statement by Senator Vandenberg to Resolutions Committee of Republican National Convention (Reel 7)
  - January-June 1945
    - January 10, 1945 "Let's Win Both the War and the Peace" (Reel 7)
    - February 25, 1945 "Lifting Government Controls" (Reel 7)
    - March 5, 1945 Statement re: San Francisco Conference (Reel 7)
    - April 9, 1945 "Land-Lease--and America's Post-War Obligations" (Reel 7)
    - April 12, 1945 Statement at death of Franklin D. Roosevelt (Reel 7)
    - May 7, 1945 Press Statement at UN Delegation (Reel 7)
    - May 9, 1945 United Nations Conference on International Organization United States Delegation Memorandum of Press and Radio News Conference (Reel 7)
    - June 29, 1945 "The Charter of the United Nations" (Reel 7)
  - July-December 1945
    - July 13, 1945 Speech to Detroit Economic Club (Reel 7)
    - September 1, 1945 AFL Radio Speech (Reel 7)
    - November 9, 1945 "Sanctity of Labor-Management Contracts" (Reel 7)
    - November 15, 1945 "Raise the Iron Curtain" (Reel 7)
  - January-March 1946
    - February 27, 1946 "Report on the United Nations Meeting in London" (Reel 7)
    - March 23, 1946 Speech at Grand Rapids "Homecoming" (Reel 7)
  - April-July 1946
    - April 22, 1946 "Proposed Loan to Great Britain" (Reel 7)
    - May 21, 1946 "Report on the Paris Peace Conference" (Reel 7)
    - July 16, 1946 "The Thorny Road Toward Peace" (Reel 7)
  - August-December 1946
    - August 14, 1946 V-J Day Speech, Ann Arbor, Michigan (Reel 7)
    - August 17, 1946 Speech to American Legion Convention (Reel 7)
    - October 14, 1946 Press Release at Paris Peace Conference. Finland Reparations. (Reel 7)
    - October 19, 1946 Radio interview from Washington Saturday night. Interviewer: George Cushing of WJR (Reel 7)
    - [October] 1946 Speech concerning navigation on the Danube River (Reel 7)
  - 1947
    - January 11, 1947 "America's Foreign Relations"-Cleveland Foreign Affairs Forum (Reel 7)
    - January 29, 1947 "American Attitude Toward Polish Elections" (Reel 7)
    - February 8, 1947 "The Republican Challenge" Address before Michigan Republican State Convention Grand Rapids (Reel 7)
    - February 21, 1947 Budget Speech. (Reel 7)
    - April 3, 1947 "Lilienthal" (Reel 7)
    - April 8, 1947 "The Whole Greek Loan Story" (Reel 7)
    - April 14, 1947 "Pan-American Day" (Reel 7)
    - June 3, 1947 "Ratify these Treaties!" (Reel 7)
    - June 6, 1947 "Borah as a Statesman" at Unveiling of William E. .Borah Statue (Reel 7)
    - November 3, 1947 University of Michigan. Ann Arbor. (Reel 7)
    - 1947 Address on Aid to Greece and Turkey (Reel 7)
  - 1948
    - January 24, 1948 Report of the Brookings Institute on the Administration of European Recovery Program (Reel 7)
    - March 1, 1948 "The Battle for World Peace and Stability" (Reel 7)
    - April 27, 1948 "The American Position" Michigan Chamber of Commerce (Reel 7)
    - October 4, 1948 Address over CBS. Republican Campaign Speech. (Reel 7)
    - October 28, 1948 Campaign Speech. Grand Rapids. (Reel 7)
    - November 11, 1948 Reception of the Reserve Officers Association Medal. (Reel 7)
    - November 22, 1948 Public Statement on Cloture problems (Reel 7)
    - December 3, 1948 Message to Pan American Union (Reel 7)
    - 1948 "Declaration of Purpose: A World of Free Men" (Reel 7)
    - 1948 "Philadelphia, 194811 [Written letter] (Reel 7)
  - January-March 1949
    - January 18, 1949 "The Acheson Nomination" (Reel 7)
    - February 10, 1949 Detroit Lincoln Dinner Speech, NBC Radio (Reel 7)
    - February 14, 1949 "The Challenge to the Republican Party" (Reel 7)
    - March 11, 1 1949 "The Debate on Senate Rules" (Reel 7)
    - March 22, 1949 National Conference of Mayors, Washington, D.C. (Reel 7)
  - April-December 1949
    - April 25, 1949 Address at Annual Award Dinner of Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Association. (Reel 7)
    - May 28, 1949 Address to meeting of Inter-American Bar Association Ann Arbor (Reel 7)
    - July 6, 1949 "The North Atlantic Treaty" (Reel 7)
    - September 15, 1949 National Press Club Address (Reel 7)
  - Undated
    - Undated, "Alexander Hamilton" (Reel 7)
    - Undated, "Franklin Dinner Address" (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning Ireland (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning Canadian-American relations (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning St. Lawrence Seaway (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning recommendations of Joint Congressional Budgetary Committee (Reel 7)
  - By topic or format
    - Speech on Supreme Court Reorganization 1937 [undelivered] (Reel 7)
    - Speech, undated, concerning nomination of Edward J. Flynn as Minister to Australia [undelivered] (Reel 7)
    - Congressional debates [tear sheets from CR] (Reel 7)
    - Congressional hearings [misc. extracts] (Reel 7)
    - Scrapbook 1929-1949 containing speeches taken from newspapers, CR, and magazines (Reel 8)
- Campaign and miscellaneous topical 1934-1948
  Campaign and Miscellaneous Topical consists of a few folders of campaign materials and two folders of topical interest. One folder concerns the death of Quentin Roosevelt during World War I. The other is a telegram from John Foster Dulles concerning plan for Japanese disarmament written after World War II.
  - Campaign materials
    - 1934 (Reel 8)
    - 1940 (Reel 8)
    - 1946 (Reel 8)
    - 1948 (Reel 8)
  - Miscellaneous topical
    - Editorial concerning death of Quentin Roosevelt; response of Theodore Roosevelt; note from H. Robinson about fabric from Q. Roosevelt's airplane July 1918 (Reel 8)
    - Telegram from John Foster Dulles concerning plan for Japanese disarmament circa 1946 (Reel 8)
- Clippings, articles, and scrapbooks 1925-1951, 1 linear feet; 25 volumes
  Clippings, Articles and Scrapbooks (1 linear ft. and 25 volumes) documents Vandenberg's life and career. The clippings cover the period of 1925-1951. Except for two earlier volumes for the years 1884-1921 and 1901-1910, the scrapbooks detail Vandenberg's senatorial career (1928-1951).
  - Magazine articles
    - By and about AHV (Reel 8)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1925-1932 (Reel 8)
    - 1933 Senate campaign (Reel 8)
    - 1934-1935 (Reel 8)
    - 1936 (miscellaneous) (Reel 8)
    - January-June 1936 (Reel 8)
    - July-September 1936 (Reel 8)
    - October-December 1936 (Reel 8)
    - 1937 (Reel 8)
    - 1938 (Reel 8)
    - January-June 1939 (Reel 8)
    - July-December 1939 (Reel 8)
    - 1939 (Presidential prospects) (Reel 8)
    - 1940 (Presidential prospects) (Reel 8)
    - January-March 1940 (Reel 8)
    - April-June 1940 (Reel 8)
    - July-December 1940 (Reel 8)
    - 1941 (Reel 8)
    - 1942 (Reel 8)
    - 1943 (Reel 9)
    - 1944 (Reel 9)
    - 1945 (Reel 9)
    - 1946 (Reel 9)
    - January-May 1947 (Reel 9)
    - June-December 1947 (Reel 9)
    - January-June 1948 (Reel 9)
    - July-December 1948 (Reel 9)
    - 1948 (re AHV's Presidential prospects) (Reel 9)
    - 1949 (Reel 9)
    - 1950 (Reel 9)
    - January-March 1951 (Reel 9)
    - April 1951 (Reel 9)
      (obituaries)
    - April 1951 (Reel 9)
      (oversize obituaries and related material)
    - April-December 1951 (Reel 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Reel 9)
    - Hazel Vandenberg (Reel 9)
    - Notebook containing newspaper articles concerning the history of G.O.P. conventions 1920 (Reel 9)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbooks and albums 1884-1951 1928-1951, 25 volumes
      (most cover Vandenberg's political career, 1928-1951)
      (Not microfilmed; available only for on-site use)
      (Located at AA)
      - 1 (Volume 1)
      - 2 (Volume 2)
      - 3 (Volume 3)
      - 4 (Volume 4)
      - 5 (Volume 5)
      - 6 (Volume 6)
      - 7 (Volume 7)
      - 8 (Volume 8)
      - 9 (Volume 9)
      - 10 (Volume 10)
      - 11 (Volume 11)
      - 12 (Volume 12)
      - 13 (Volume 13)
      - 14 (Volume 14)
      - 15 (Volume 15)
      - 16 (Volume 16)
      - 17 (Volume 17)
      - 18 (Volume 18)
      - 19 (Volume 19)
      - 20 (Volume 20)
      - 21 (Volume 21)
      - 22 (Volume 22)
      - 23 (Volume 23)
      - 24 (Volume 24)
      - 25 (Volume 25)
- Miscellaneous and personal
  Miscellaneous and Personal consists of memorabilia and various other personal material, some of great importance such as the diaries Vandenberg kept while participating in the United Nations Conference which took place in San Francisco in 1945 and while attending the Paris Peace Conference in 1946.
  - Notebook containing excerpts from AHV's Private Papers of Senator Vandenberg, 1952 (Reel 9)
  - Miscellaneous items (Reel 9)
  - AHV will and inventory of estate (Reel 9)
  - Income tax materials (Reel 9)
  - Genealogical materials (Reel 9)
  - Degrees, honorary degrees, miscellaneous citations (Reel 9)
  - Oversize citations and memorabilia (Reel 9)
  - Miscellaneous programs, invitations, etc. (Reel 9)
  - Dedication materials: Arthur H. Vandenberg School, AHV Room (Reel 9)
  - Papers concerning dedication of AHV Room, Bentley Historical Library 1974 (Reel 9)
  - Printed material largely concerning the Florida Ship Canal (Reel 10)
  - AHV Congressional voting record 1945-1951 (Reel 10)
    (taken from the Blair Moody papers)
  - Notebook containing record of votes in Senate 1950 (Reel 10)
  - AHV diary re: San Francisco Charter Conference on U.N., March-June 1945 (Reel 10)
  - AHV diary re: Paris Peace Conference: 1st Session, April-May; 2nd Session, June-July; and Council of Foreign Ministers, 1946 (Reel 10)
  - Scrapbook largely concerning AHV's Alexander Hamilton biography 1921-1923 (Reel 10)
  - Volume: In Memoriam, Elizabeth Watson Vandenberg (Reel 10)
  - Volume: In Memoriam, Arthur H. Vandenberg (Reel 10)
  - Passports, 5 items (Reel 11)
  - Charter of the United Nations, 2 volumes (Reel 11)
  - Congressional hearings on The Vandenberg Resolution and the North Atlantic Treaty, 2 volumes (Reel 11)
  - Volume: The Congressional Awards; established by Collier's (Reel 11)
- Visual Materials
  Visual Materials includes photographs, a motion picture, and a few newspaper political cartoon drawings.
  - Photographs
    The Photographs subseries includes portraits and photos of friends and colleagues. There are also photos of the United Nations Conference and the U.S. Senate. (Photographs were microfilmed and appear on Roll 11)
    - Awards and honors (Box 7)
    - Campaigns (Box 7)
    - Family (Box 7)
    - Family (with AHV) (Box 7)
    - Friends and colleagues (Box 7)
    - United Nations Conference (with Harry Truman, George Marshall) (Box 7)
    - United States Senate (with Robert Taft, Wendell Willkie) (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
      - As speaker (Box 7)
      - Early photos, including tintypes, shots of military parade, interior of his office (Box 7)
      - Portraits, formal (Box 7)
      - Portraits, informal (Box 7)
      - Portraits, early (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr. (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr., in military (Harry Truman) (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Hazel Whitaker
      - Early photos (Box 7)
      - Portraits (Box 7)
    - Album circa 1895-1897, With photographs and memorabilia (Box 7)
    - Oversize photographs: Class pictures, family portraits, formal and informal shots, and photos concerning senate and political career (Box 9)
  - Cartoons
    (The cartoons were microfilmed and appear on Roll 11.)
    - "No Going Ashore" by Dowling 1948 (Box 9)
    - "Don't Spare the Rod Too Long" by C. Orr 1948, Chicago Tribune (Box 9)
    - "The Fable of the Bullfrog and the Ox" by C. Orr 1947, Chicago Tribune (Box 9)
    - "Something More Vital" by Poinier January 3, 1948, Detroit Free Press (Box 9)
    - "Distracting-To Say the Least!" by Frank (?) August 9, 1939 (Box 9)
    - "I'll Concede This One", by Frank (?) August 9, 1939 (Box 9)
  - Motion Pictures
    The film subseries consists of a 16mm black-and-white film of the United Nations San Francisco Conference. A VHS copy of this film is available for research examination.
    - Film showing highlights and participants in U.N. Conference on International Organization, San Francisco with U.S. delegation at end 1945, 16mm, black and white, on 7 inch reel (Box 8)
    - Video cassette (3/4 inch) copy of, 1945 film (Box 8)
- Sound Recordings
  Sound Recordings consists of phonograph record discs of various Vandenberg speeches, some of which were given on the radio. There is also one reel-to reel tape of a 1936 radio speech given in the form of a debate with President Roosevelt.
  - Sound discs
    - Speech in Chicago with Crosswell excerpts October 17, 1936, 4 phonograph records 78 rpm; 7 sides
      (transcribed December 8, 1949)
    - WXYZ Michigan Radio Network January 5, 1945, 4 phonograph records 78 rpm
    - "Future Republican Party Objectives" (Lincoln's Day Dinner February 10, 1949, 3 phonograph records 78 rpm
    - War aims speech circa 1943, 1 phonograph records 78 rpm
    - Pan American Day speech April 14, 1947, 1 phonograph records
    - "Fight for Peace" (re-election campaign speech; parts I and II), 2 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm
      (cassette copy in Box 8)
    - "Stop the Drums" (WJR radio speech) December 7, 1946, 2 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm
    - Report to the People July 26, 1949, 1 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm
  - Sound tape reel
    - Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg replies to recorded statements by President Franklin Roosevelt, 1936, 1 reel-to-reel audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches (Box 1)
      - [Part 1], [86746-SR-1-1]; (Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg plays recorded statements made by Franklin Delano Roosevelt and comments on issues raised. Recorded in form of debate.)
Selective Index to Correspondence
Acheson, Dean Gooderham, 1893-1971.
July 9, August 5, August 9, August 12, August 13, 1946; January 14, January 24, January 28, February 5, March 4, March 6, March 19, March 20, March 24, March 25, June 20, 1947
September 29, November 25, December 6, 1949; January 3, January 18, January 23, February 3, April 10, June 12, July 7, November 6, December 6, 1950; January 9, 1951.
Aiken, George David, 1892-
November 8, 1946, January 15, 1951 (see also folder 6-7)
American Profit Sharing Institute